Pelke, Bill; Papers apap205
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Bill Pelke Papers
1965-2007, Undated
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
apap205
18.32 cubic feet
Bill Pelke is a leader in the national death penalty abolition movement. This collection documents Bill Pelke's involvement with Journey of Hope...from Violence to Healing, Murder Victims' Families for Reconciliation (MVFR), National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty (NCADP), Amnesty International, and other organizations committed to ending capital punishment in the United States.
Acquisition Information
Bill Pelke donated these records to the M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives in a series of two acquisitions in 2005 and 2006.
Biographical History
Bill Pelke was born in 1947 in Indiana. In 1985, Bill Pelkes grandmother Ruth Elizabeth Pelke, a 78 year old bible school teacher was brutally murdered in her home by a group of high school girls during a robbery. The leader of the group responsible, Paula Cooper (15), was arrested and was found guilty and sentenced to die. At first, Bill Pelke believed this to be a just punishment but later, owing to a realization that his grandmother would show mercy, began advocating for a retraction of Paula Coopers death sentence. In 1989, Paula Coopers sentence was changed from death to 60 years, owing to recent changes in federal and state laws which barred the death penalty for defendants who committed crimes under the age of 16.
Bill Pelke was very active in the death penalty abolition movement both locally and nationally. He was the President/Co-Founder of Journey of Hope From Violence to Healing, that began as a two-week event conducted by Murder Victims Families for Reconciliation (MVFR) in which speakers told the story of their loss and their resolution to oppose the death penalty. Journey of Hope conducted yearly events beginning in 1993 in Indiana, and followed by events in Georgia (1994), California (1995), and Virginia (1996). In 1997, Journey of Hope was spun-off from MVFR and became its own organization called Journey of HopeFrom Violence to Healing. The same year, Bill Pelke who was a member of both boards left MVFR. After its incorporation, Journey of HopeFrom Violence to Healing has organized full two-week events, as well as a number of smaller events, in states throughout the United States and overseas; Philippines (1998), Italy (1998), Europe (1998, 1999), Germany (2009), and Uganda, Rwanda, and Kenya (2011).
In the last quarter of his life, Bill Pelke was a member in various capacities for the National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty (NCADP), Murder Victims Families for Human Rights (MVFHR), Alaskans Against the Death Penalty (AADP), Abolitionist Action Committee (AAC), Citizens United for Alternatives to the Death Penalty (CUADP), Indiana Citizens United for the Rehabilitation of Errants (Indiana CURE), Amnesty International, and Murder Victims Families for Reconciliation (MVFR).
Bill Pelke was a retired steelworker, a Vietnam veteran, and a college graduate with a BS degree in Pastoral Theology. He authored the book, Journey of Hope...from Violence to Healing, which details the murder of his grandmother Ruth Elizabeth Pelke. At the time of his death from a heart attack in November 2020 he lived in Alaska and was actively involved with the abolitionist movement.
Scope and Contents
The collections documents Bill Pelke's efforts to abolish the death penalty in the United States from the late 1980s to the early 2000s. The collection includes organizing material for Journey of Hope...from Violence to Healing and Murder Victims' Families for Reconciliation (MVFR) as well as materials from Amnesty International and the National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty (NCADP). It also includes correspondence, publications, and materials related to various national, regional, state, and local activist organizations, non-profit groups, and religious organizations concerned with the death penalty and other activism related activities and events.
Arrangement of the Collection
Researchers should note that the collection contained no original order and was arranged by the archivist.
Related Materials
Related collections include
Murder Victims Families for Reconciliation Records, 1994-2005; the
Abraham Bonowitz Papers, 1995-2009; and
National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty Records, 1972-2006, Undated
.
Death Penalty; Criminal Justice and Prisons; Capital punishment--United States; Executions and executioners--United States; Death row--United States; Newsletters; Newspaper clippings; Photographs; Legal documents; Correspondence; Articles; Pamphlets; Minutes (administrative records); Brochures; Pelke, Bill; Amnesty International; National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty (U.S.); Murder Victims Families for Reconciliation; Journey of Hope...from Violence to Healing
- Correspondence, 1967-1999, Undated; 1; 1.6 cubic feet
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains the correspondence directed to Bill Pelke, as well as a small amount of correspondence from Bill Pelke. This includes correspondence from death row inmates and fellow activists. Correspondence from activist groups is included in the Activism series; however researchers should note that because of the nature of activist groups, one individual may be involved in many groups. In the event of one individual with correspondence from many groups the correspondence has been assembled together under the activists name.
  - James Allridge III, 1992; 1994-1995 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 1)
  - Johann Christoph Arnold- Bruderhof Communities, 1996-1998; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 2)
  - Robert Auker, 1992-1994 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 3)
  - Pat Bane, 1990-1994; 1997-1998; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 4)
  - Alan J. Bannister, 1994-1995 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 5)
  - Lindsay Bannister, 1994-1995 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - Helen E. Barker, 1993; 1997 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 7)
  - Judy Bellin, 1995; 1997 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Larry Bellmore, 1991-1992 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - Noe Beltran, 1993-1994 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Gerald Bivens, 1993-1996 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Jerry Blanchard- " Blanchard and Associates ", 1994-1995 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Melanie Bloom, 1992-1993 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 13)
  - Hugo Boniche, 1995 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 14)
  - Abraham Bonowitz, 1991-1998; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 15)
  - Fr. Vito N. Bracon, 1987; 1989; 1992; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 16)
  - James Brewe, 1991-1992 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 17)
  - John Brown, 1993 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 18)
  - Ariel Brugger, 1996 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 19)
  - Karen Burkhart, 1993; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 20)
  - Gini Burns, 1997 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 21)
  - Callie & Wanda Callahan, 1991-1992 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 22)
  - Roger Carroll, 1991 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 23)
  - Buff Carmichael, 1991 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 24)
  - Susan Cary, 1993 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 25)
  - Marvin Castor, 1991 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 26)
  - Lorig Charkovdlan, 1995-1996; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 27)
  - Claudia, 1992; 1995; 1997; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 28)
  - David Cohen, 1993; 1995 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 29)
  - Kevin Connor, 1992-1993 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 30)
  - Paula Cooper?, 1986-1988; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 31)
  - George Cordova, 1992 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 32)
  - Carol Curtis, 1993 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 33)
  - Mark Daniel, 1992 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 34)
  - Rodney Dean, 1992-1993 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 35)
  - Marie Deans, 1991; 1993; 1995; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 36)
  - Micki Dickoff, Sonia Jacobs- " Pro Bono Productions ", 1994; 1996-1997; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 37)
  - Shirley Dicks, 1993-1997; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 38)
  - Susan Dillow, 1993-1994 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 39)
  - Leigh Dixon, 1991-1992 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 40)
  - Barbara Doughts and David Victor, 1992-1995 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 41)
  - Rev. Charles Doyle, 1995-1996 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 42)
  - LaRamon Durkham, 1992 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 43)
  - Debra Jo Elsmore, 1993 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 44)
  - Charles Evans, 1993 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 45)
  - Norman Felton, 1986; 1991; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 46)
  - Paul Ferrini- " Miracles Community Network ", 1996; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 47)
  - Randolph Fowler, 1993 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 48)
  - Mark D. Franckiewicz, 1992-1995 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 49)
  - Judy Gage, 1992; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 50)
  - Aba Gayle, 1994-1995; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 51)
  - General Correspondence, 1977; 1986 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 52)
  - General Correspondence, 1987 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 53)
  - General Correspondence, 1988 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 54)
  - General Correspondence, 1989 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 55)
  - General Correspondence, 1990 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 56)
  - General Correspondence, 1991 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 57)
  - General Correspondence, 1992 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 58)
  - General Correspondence, 1992 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 59)
  - General Correspondence, 1993 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 60)
  - General Correspondence, 1993 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 61)
  - General Correspondence, 1994 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 62)
  - General Correspondence, 1995 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 63)
  - General Correspondence, 1996 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 64)
  - General Correspondence, 1997 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 65)
  - General Correspondence, 1998 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 66)
  - General Correspondence, 1999 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 67)
  - General Correspondence, Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 68)
  - General Correspondence, Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 69)
  - Stephanie Gibson, 1997-1998; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 70)
  - Harrison Gratium, 1992; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 71)
  - Suzanne Gray - "Janey Appleseed", 1992; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 72)
  - John Greenya, 1991 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 73)
  - Brian Greulach, 1993 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 74)
  - Rachel Gross, 1992-1993; 1995-1996; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 75)
  - Leif Halvorson, 1993; 1995 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 76)
  - William Hance, 1992 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 77)
  - James Harrison, 1992; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 78)
  - Charles " Mike " Hedlund, 1990; 1997 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 79)
  - Holiday Cards, 1992-1998; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 80)
  - Holiday Cards, 1992-1999; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 81)
  - Jerry Holsopple, 1996; 1998 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 82)
  - Richard Huttman, 1991-1992; 1997; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 83)
  - Mary Hutchinson, 1993-1998; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 84)
  - Mary Hutchinson, 1993-1998; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 85)
  - Keiko Ichiye, 1992 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 86)
  - Gregory Scott Johnson, 1991 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 87)
  - Kathryn Johnson, 1993 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 88)
  - Martin and Burgel Johnson, 1997-1998 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 89)
  - Rayfield Renee Johnson, 1994-1995 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 90)
  - Rickey Johnson, 1992 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 91)
  - Brandon Astor Jones, 1996-1997 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 92)
  - Bruce Karriem, 1993; 1995 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 93)
  - Kathy, ca. 1998 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 94)
  - Marilyn Kerstine, 1996 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 95)
  - Khalfeni Khaldum, 1995 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 96)
  - Jayce Kimbrough, 1992 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 97)
  - Susan Kimmelman, 1993; Undated (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 98)
  - Charlie King, 1993; 1995-1996 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 99)
  - Art Koeninger, 1997 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 100)
  - Daisy Kouzel, 1992-1994 (Box 1 (1-Correspondence), Folder 101)
  - Nina Kraut, 1998 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 1)
  - Jon Krieg, 1992 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 2)
  - Louis Lafleur, 1995 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 3)
  - Laura, 1993; Undated (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 4)
  - Mike Lawson, 1995; Undated (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 5)
  - Ronald Lee, ca. 1994; 1995; 1996 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - Sandra Levy, 1993 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 7)
  - Ed Loring, 1993 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Eugenio Maggi, 1993 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - Jaeger Marrieta, 1992-1994; 1997; Undated (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Teresa Mathis, 1993-1994; 1998; Undated (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Walter McCarthy, 1995; 1997 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Julia McKiernan, 1995; 1997 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 13)
  - Lowanna McQuay, 1995 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 14)
  - Lotte Meyerson, 1995-1996 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 15)
  - Steven Miller, 1991-1992; Undated (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 16)
  - Dorothy J. Miller - EL, 1995 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 17)
  - William Minnick, 1992-1993 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 18)
  - Nora Mitchell, 1994 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 19)
  - Mom and Dad, 1993; 1995; 1998; Undated (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 20)
  - Mary Moriarty, 1995 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 21)
  - Andre Moses, 1995; Undated (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 22)
  - Maria Cristina Mossa, 1993-1996 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 23)
  - Claude Moturana, 1993 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 24)
  - Kondo Nassor/Resnover, 1992; 1994 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 25)
  - Michael Nolte, 1995 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 26)
  - Kathy Norgard, 1993; 1995; 1997 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 27)
  - Richard Odom, 1993 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 28)
  - Governor Robert D. Orr, 1987 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 29)
  - John Osbourne, 1994-1995 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 30)
  - Harold LaMont Otey 'Willi', 1992-1993 (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 31)
  - Sara Otrusina, 1993-1994; 1996-1997; Undated (Box 2 (1-Correspondence), Folder 32)
  - Helen ' Pajama Lady ' Pajama, 1990-1997; Undated (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 1)
  - Bill Pelke, 1967-1968; 1986-1988; 1991-1997; Undated (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 2)
  - Steve and Michelle Phlmeyer, 1992; 1996-1998 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 3)
  - George Porter, 1992 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 4)
  - Potter - Johnson Family, 1992; 1994-1995; 1997 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 5)
  - Dubley Powell, 1992 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - Kai Ransom, 1993; Undated (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 7)
  - Troy Reimer, 1994; 1997; Undated (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Dennis " Ray " Roark, 1991-1992; 1991/1992 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - Charles Roche, 1991-1993 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Eugenio Rodriguez, 1992 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Sonia Rosen, 1992; Undated (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Kurt Rosenberg, 1996; Undated (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 13)
  - Michael Ross, 1992-1998 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 14)
  - Kaori Sakagam, Undated (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 15)
  - Marla Sandys, 1991; 1994 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 16)
  - Ronald Schackart, 1993; 1995 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 17)
  - Donna Schneweis, 1992-1995; Undated (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 18)
  - Don Schrader, 1993 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 19)
  - Matt Schroeder, 1993 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 20)
  - Lee Seiber, 1993 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 21)
  - Al' Hadeed Shabazz, 1993; 1995 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 22)
  - Michael Sharp, 1992-1995 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 23)
  - Karl Shelly, 1991; 1994-1995 (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 24)
  - Sam Sheppard, 1989-1990; 1992-1995; 1997; Undated (Box 3 (1-Correspondence), Folder 25)
  - Tom Shiro, 1992-1993 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 1)
  - Darlene Smith, 1992-1993 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 2)
  - Joe Smith Jr., 1992 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 3)
  - Jerry Springer, 1992 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 4)
  - DeCourcy Squire, Undated (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 5)
  - J. Stack, 1997 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 6)
  - John Stahl, 1997 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 7)
  - David F. Stamps, 1992-1993; 1995; Undated (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Michael Stanch, 1992-1993 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 9)
  - Beatrice Streckx - Lefebvre, 1995-1996 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Mr. and Mrs. R. Stone, 1993 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Lorenzo Stone - Bay, 1993-1996; 1998; Undated (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Glen Sweet, 1993; 1998 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 13)
  - Paul Taylor, 1993 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 14)
  - Robert Teffeteller, 1997 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 15)
  - Maria Telesco, 1993; 1995 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 16)
  - Craig Thompson, 1993 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 17)
  - Linda M. Thurtson, 1992; 1994 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 18)
  - Mary Louise Tillery, 1994 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 19)
  - Maureen Timmins, 1993-1994 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 20)
  - William Touchette, 1987 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 21)
  - Robert Turner, 1993 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 22)
  - John T. Vance, 1993 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 23)
  - Johanna Vennstrom, 1992-1993 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 24)
  - Susan Vitale, 1992 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 25)
  - Charle R. Wagner, 1993 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 26)
  - Lee Webster, 1992; 1996 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 27)
  - Ned Welsh, 1989 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 28)
  - November West, 1991-1997 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 29)
  - Edward Williams, 1993 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 30)
  - Meredith Sue Willis, 1993 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 31)
  - Mark Allen Wisehart, 1991 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 32)
  - Patrick Wright, 1987; 1989; 1991-1993; Undated (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 33)
  - Sahir Hassan Zahir, 1992-1993 (Box 4 (1-Correspondence), Folder 34)
- Publications, 1974-2003, Undated; 2; 1.15 cubic feet
  This series contains published materials owned or sent to Bill Pelke. This series contains mostly newspaper, magazine, and journal articles related to the death penalty or Bill Pelke himself. Not included are materials created by activist groups such as newsletters, reports, and other such publications.
  - The American University Law Review, 1995 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 1)
  - " The Anatomy of Melancholy " by Andrew Solomon, 1998 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 2)
  - Articles, 1978-1979 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 3)
  - Articles, 1982 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 4)
  - Articles, 1983 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 5)
  - Articles, 1984 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 6)
  - Articles, 1985 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 7)
  - Articles, 1986 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 8)
  - Articles, 1987 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 9)
  - Articles, 1988 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 10)
  - Articles, 1989 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 11)
  - Articles, 1990 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 12)
  - Articles, 1991 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 13)
  - Articles, 1992 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 14)
  - Articles, 1993 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 15)
  - Articles, 1994 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 16)
  - Articles, 1995 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 17)
  - Articles, 1996 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 18)
  - Articles, 1997 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 19)
  - Articles, 1998 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 20)
  - Articles, 2003 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 21)
  - Articles, Undated (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 22)
  - " Capital Punishment of Female Offenders " by Victor Streib, 1994 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 23)
  - " Capital Punishment of Female Offenders " by Victor Streib, 1995 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 24)
  - " Capital Punishment of Female Offenders " by Victor Streib, 1996 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 25)
  - " Capital Punishment of Female Offenders " by Victor Streib, 1997-1998 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 26)
  - Chicago Tribune Magazine, 1994 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 27)
  - " Civil Disobedience Organizing " by Ed Hedemann, Undated (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 28)
  - Christian Ethics - Michael Sharp, Undated (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 29)
  - Columbia, 1995 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 30)
  - Courting Death, 1988 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 31)
  - Current Events, 1987 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 32)
  - " Dare to Dream " by Kenneth Copeland, Undated (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 33)
  - " Death Penalty Sentencing: Research Indicated Pattern of Racial Disparities " - Report to Senate and House Committees on the Judiciary, 1990 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 34)
  - Detroit Free Press Magazine, 1995 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 35)
  - " Efficacy of Prayer " by Leader Olumba Olumba Obu, Undated (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 36)
  - Famine Can We Survive, 1974 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 37)
  - Free at Last: A History of the Civil Rights Movement and Those who Died in the Struggle, 1989 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 38)
  - Georgetown Journal on Fighting Poverty, 1996 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 39)
  - Georgia State University Law Review, 1998 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 40)
  - " Habeas Corpus as a Crucial Protector of Constitutional Rights " by Ronald J. Tabak - Seton Hall Law Review, 1996 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 41)
  - The Houston Law Review, 1994 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 42)
  - Human Rights and Human Wrongs, ca.1997 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 43)
  - Impact, 1995 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 44)
  - " Imposition of Death Sentences for Juvenile Offenses " by Victor Streib, 1990 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 45)
  - In These Times, 1993 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 46)
  - " Innocence and the Death Penalty ", Staff report by the Subcommittee on Civil and Constituional Rights, 1993 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 47)
  - " The Juvenile Death Penalty in the United States and Worldwide " by Victor Streib, 1997 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 48)
  - " The Juvenile Death Penalty Today " by Victor Streib, 1994 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 49)
  - " The Juvenile Death Penalty Today " by Victor Streib, 1995 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 50)
  - " The Juvenile Death Penalty Today " by Victor Streib, 1996-1998 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 51)
  - " Keeper of the Flame " - chapter by John G. Healey, 1989 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 52)
  - " A Layperson's Guide for Communication with People in Prison " - by Mark D. Fronckiewicz, 1993 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 53)
  - " Leaven of Forgiveness " by Mary Sue Penn, 1997 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 54)
  - " Life and Liberty " by Vasu Murti, Undated (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 55)